We all love to take photographs.
我们都喜欢拍照。
It's a simple way to capture a special moment, an amazing view, or just to show off your artistic skills.
这是一种捕捉特殊时刻、迷人风光或展示艺术技巧的简单方式。
And it's great to look back through your photo albums and share your memories with friends.
翻阅相册并与朋友分享回忆也很棒。
In essence, they show a snapshot in time.
从本质上讲，照片展示了某个时刻的快照。
This hasn't really changed since the invention of photography in the 1830s.
自19世纪30年代摄影术发明以来，这一点并未真正改变。
But one thing that has changed, is the equipment we use.
但有一个变化是我们使用的设备。
For many years, we have used traditional cameras to take our pictures with.
多年来，我们一直使用传统相机拍照。
Our images were captured onto camera film which was then processed into negatives from which photos were printed – a lengthy process.
图像被捕捉到胶卷上，然后再被处理成底片，再从中冲印照片——这是一个漫长的过程。
And we've had a range of cameras to choose from – from the simple compact camera to more sophisticated SLR cameras (single lens reflex).
我们有一系列相机可供选择——从简单的袖珍相机到更复杂的单反相机（单镜头反光相机）。
But the biggest change has come with the development of digital technology.
但最大的变化来自数字技术的发展。
This has made taking photos quicker and easier.
这使得拍照更快更简单。
It's enabled us to take a snap and review our pictures instantly.
它让我们能够快速拍摄并立即查看照片。
We've been able to manipulate them in post-production, using software on our computer.
我们可以在后期制作中使用电脑软件对照片进行处理。
And of course, we've been able to share them like never before – particularly on social media.
当然，我们也能以前所未有的方式分享照片——尤其是在社交媒体上。
Of course, now we have the smartphone – a phone that is, well, smart because it can take photos and sometime very good quality ones, and share them easily.
当然，我们现在有了智能手机——之所以称其为“智能”，是因为它可以拍照，有时画质还很好，并且易于分享。
So does that mean the traditional camera will eventually become obsolete?
那么这是否意味着传统相机会最终被淘汰？
Figures from Japan show how the market is shrinking: shipments of compact digital cameras from companies like Olympus, Canon and Nikon were down 39% year on year.
日本的数据显示市场正在萎缩：奥林巴斯、佳能和尼康等公司的袖珍数码相机出货量同比下降了39%。
But Phil Hall, editor of Tech Radar magazine thinks there's nothing to worry about.
但《技术雷达》杂志编辑菲尔・霍尔认为无需担心。
He told the BBC that while people are swapping their compact cameras for smartphones, "manufacturers are looking at the more higher-end premium cameras, high-end compacts, DSLRs, which are the ones you can attach lenses to, mirrorless cameras."
他告诉BBC，虽然人们正在用智能手机取代袖珍相机，“制造商正在关注更高端的优质相机，如高端袖珍相机、可更换镜头的单反相机（DSLR）和无反相机。”
Certainly, the growth of the smartphone means more and more of us are taking photos and it opens our eyes to the creative possibilities it can provide.
当然，智能手机的普及意味着越来越多的人在拍照，它也让我们看到了其带来的创意可能性。
And for some, it can be a first step into getting into serious photography and pushing their creative skills.
对一些人来说，这可能是进入专业摄影并提升创意技能的第一步。
But whatever camera viewfinder we end up looking through, it's important to remember the basics of focussing, good lighting and framing - and getting your subject to say 'cheese!'
但无论我们最终使用哪种相机的取景器，重要的是记住对焦、良好光线和构图的基础知识——以及让拍摄对象说“茄子”！